The operator told me the GPS failed under a tunnel.
Black Box checked the recording and said: that story is wrong.
Robotics teams collect hours of video, lidar, telemetry,
and controller logs.
The evidence exists, but forensic review is still manual.
One real driving session. No labels.
Just the operator's note: check the tunnel.
Black Box opens it as a forensic case.
Not a one-shot summary.
Opus 4.7 runs as a managed forensic agent —
reading files, calling tools, streaming events.
Memory carries forward across runs.
It doesn't send every frame.
Telemetry selects suspicious windows.
High-resolution visual mining checks the relevant cameras.
The tunnel did mildly degrade GNSS.
But the RTK heading failure was already present
43 minutes earlier.
Drive-by-wire was never engaged.
The tunnel could not have caused this.
Operator hypothesis: refuted.
The real failure is lower level.
Moving-base antenna: healthy.
Rover: never receives valid RTK heading.
The correction path was broken before the car left the lot.
The output isn't just a report.
Scoped patch: RTCM IDs, UART link check,
and a human-review gate.
Black Box proposes. Engineer approves.
Same benchmark slice. Opus 4.6 vs 4.7.
Same cases, same prompts, same budget.
On simple post-mortems they tie.
But robot forensics punishes confident wrong answers.
4.6 committed on every under-specified case.
4.7 abstained every time.
Not a single-car demo.
More car sessions. A robotic boat case.
Clean recordings and injected benchmark failures.
When evidence is weak, it refuses to invent a bug.
No evidence. No claim.
Open benchmark. Reproducible runs.
Robot forensics in minutes, for cents.