Operator told me the GPS failed when the car
went under a tunnel.
I gave the bag to Black Box. It said he was wrong.
AV labs process hundreds of bags per week.
Nobody reads them end-to-end.
Everybody has a theory. Most theories are wrong.
One hour of real driving. ROS1 bag. No labels.
Operator handed over one sentence: "check the tunnel."
Opus 4.7 reads the telemetry. Carrier-phase,
fix quality, relative-position validity.
Long-horizon agent loop. Native memory.
Streaming events. Source badge: REPLAY — real.
Moving-base antenna: clean RTK 94% of the bag.
Rover antenna: never locks. Once. The whole hour.
REL_POS_VALID never sets. Dual-antenna heading
pipeline broken before the car left the lot.
Operator blamed the tunnel.
Black Box: heading subsystem failed at t=0.24s,
forty-three minutes before tunnel entry.
Operator hypothesis REFUTED.
This is the fix. Specific RTCM3 message IDs:
1077, 1087, 1097, 1127, 4072.0, 4072.1.
Config diff, not a redesign.
Proposed for human review — not auto-applied.
Same single-shot accuracy as 4.6.
Better judgment. More eyes.
Abstains 100% on under-specified cases (4.6: 0%).
Better Brier under wrong operator framing.
Reads small text 4.6 downsamples away.
Other car runs. A robotic boat.
A clean synthetic bag.
Same pipeline. Different robots. Honest verdicts.
Same tool, clean bag. Returns nothing anomalous.
Will not fabricate a bug. Hypotheses dropped
below evidence threshold. NO_ANOMALY_PATCH.
One hour of real driving. Forty-six cents.
Benchmark open on GitHub: black-box-bench.
Black Box · Forensic copilot for robots
Built with Opus 4.7