The operator told me the GPS failed under a tunnel. Black Box checked the recording and said: that story is wrong.
Robotics teams collect hours of video, lidar, telemetry and controller logs. The evidence exists, but the forensic work is still manual.
I give Black Box one real driving session. No labels. No handcrafted rubric. Just the operator's note: check the tunnel.
This is not a one-shot summary. Opus 4.7 runs as a managed forensic agent: reading files, using tools, streaming events, checking memory from previous runs.
It does not send every frame. Telemetry selects suspicious windows, then high-resolution visual mining checks the relevant camera views.
Here is the key moment. The tunnel did mildly degrade GNSS. But the RTK heading failure was already present 43 minutes earlier, and drive-by-wire was never engaged. The tunnel could not have caused the reported behavior change.
The real failure is lower level. The moving-base antenna is healthy, but the rover never gets valid RTK heading. The correction path was broken before the car left the lot.
The output is not just a report. It gives a scoped patch: RTCM message IDs, a UART link check, and a human-review gate. Black Box proposes the diff; the engineer approves it.
This is why Black Box is built on Opus 4.7. Not because simple cases need a bigger model — 4.6 and 4.7 tie there. But robot forensics punishes confident wrong answers. In our benchmark, 4.6 committed on every under-specified case. 4.7 abstained every time.
It also sees fine visual details that 4.6 loses under downsampling, and runs about thirty percent faster on telemetry and text runs.
This is not a single-car demo. The same archive includes more car sessions, a robotic boat lidar case, clean recordings, and injected benchmark failures.
When there is no evidence, it makes no claim. Open benchmark. Reproducible runs. Robot forensics in minutes, for cents.