Operator: "GPS failed under the tunnel."
Black Box checked the recording.
That story is wrong.
Hours of video, lidar, telemetry, controller logs.
Evidence exists. Forensic review is still manual.
One real driving session. No labels.
Operator's note: check the tunnel.
Not a one-shot summary.
Opus 4.7 runs as a managed forensic agent.
Tools, memory, streaming events.
Project memory carries forward across runs.
Doesn't send every frame.
Telemetry selects suspicious windows.
High-res visual mining checks relevant cameras.
The tunnel mildly degraded GNSS.
But the RTK heading failure started
43 minutes earlier.
Drive-by-wire was never engaged.
The tunnel could not have caused this.
Verdict: operator hypothesis refuted.
Cause sits lower in the stack.
Operator hypothesis: refuted.
Moving-base antenna: healthy.
Rover: never receives valid RTK heading.
Correction path broken before leaving the lot.
carr=NONE 100%. REL_POS_VALID never set.
Findings written to a forensic report.
Output isn't a report — it's a scoped patch.
RTCM message IDs. UART link check.
Plus a human-review gate.
Black Box proposes. Engineer approves.
Opus 4.7 vs 4.6, same benchmark slice.
Same accuracy. Better judgment.
4.7 sees fine visual details 4.6 loses.
On under-specified cases, 4.7 abstains.
Not a single-car demo.
More cars. A robotic boat.
Clean recordings and injected failures.
When evidence is weak, it refuses to invent a bug.
No evidence. No claim.
Open benchmark. Reproducible runs.
Robot forensics in minutes, for cents.